Welcome back. In this video, I'm going to outline a general algorithm for recursive
欢迎回来。在这段视频中，我将概述递归的一般算法
descent parsing. Before I dive into the details of the recursive descent parsing
下降解析。在深入了解递归下降解析的细节之前
algorithm, let me justify a couple of small things that we're going to use
算法，让我来证明我们要用到的几个小东西
throughout this video. Token is going to be a type and we're gonna be writing codes
在这段视频中。Token将是一种类型，我们将编写代码
and so token would be the type of all the tokens. And the particular tokens that
因此令牌将是所有令牌的类型。以及特定的令牌，
we'll use in the example are things like int, open-pare, close-paren, + and and
我们将在该示例中使用int、open-pare、close-paren、+和AND之类的内容
so token is a type and these things are instances, values of that type. And then
所以Token是一种类型，这些东西是实例，是该类型的值。然后
we're going to need a global variable called next that points to the next token
我们将需要一个名为next的全局变量，它指向下一个令牌
in the input string. And if you recall from the previous video, we used a big
在输入字符串中。如果你还记得之前的视频，我们用了一个很大的
arrow to point into the input to indicate our current position. The global variable
箭头指向输入以指示我们的当前位置。全局变量
next is going to play the same role in our code. So let's begin. The first thing
Next将在我们的代码中扮演相同的角色。那么让我们开始吧。第一件事是
we're going to do is define a number of Boolean functions and one function we have
我们要做的是定义一些布尔函数和我们拥有的一个函数
to define is one that matches the given token in the input. So how does this work?
要定义的是与输入中的给定令牌匹配的令牌。那么这是怎么运作的呢？
Well, it takes this argument, a token, okay this is a type token again. And, and
它接受这个参数，一个令牌，好的，这又是一个类型令牌。还有，还有
then it just checks whether that matches what's currently pointed to in the input
然后，它只检查它是否与输入中当前指向的内容匹配
string so is t okay equal to the thing pointed by next and notice there's a side
字符串，那么是否可以等于下一个所指的对象，请注意有一个侧面
effect, we increment the next pointer. And what's returned then is a Boolean. This is
效果，我们递增下一个指针。然后返回的是一个布尔值。这是
either true or false. So yes the token that we passed in matches the input or no
对或错。所以是的，我们传递的令牌与输入匹配还是不匹配
it doesn't. And again, just to stress this, those at the next pointer is
不是这样的。再次强调一下，下一个指针上的那些
incremented regardless of whether the match succeeded or failed. Now, another
无论匹配成功还是失败，都会递增。现在，又来了一个
thing we need to check for a matchup is the int production of asset. This is a
我们需要检查匹配的是资产的内部生产。这是一个
particular production of a particular nonterminal s. And we'll denote that by a
特定非终结点s的特定结果。我们将用一个
function that returns a Boolean and is written as s sub n. So this is, this is a
返回布尔值的函数，写为s subn。所以这是，这是一个
function that only checks for the success of one production of s. And when that, I
函数，该函数只检查s的一次生产是否成功。
won't write out the code for that now, we'll see that in a minute. And then we're
现在不会写出代码，我们马上就会看到。然后我们就会
gonna need another func tion that tries all the productions of s so this one is
我需要另一个函数来尝试s的所有结果，所以这个函数是
going to be called just s with no subscript, no subscript and so with this
将只调用s，不带下标，也不带下标，因此
one, we'll succeed if any production of s can match the input, alright. So we're
第一，如果s的任何产品都能匹配输入，我们就会成功，好吧。所以我们要
going to have two classes of functions for each nonterminal. One class that where
每个非终端都有两类函数。一节课，在那里
there's one function per production and it checks, it checks just whether that
每个产品有一个函数，它检查，它只检查是否
production can match the input and then one that combines all the productions for
产品可以与输入匹配，然后是将所有产品组合在一起的产品
that particular nonterminal together and checks whether any of them can match the
该特定非终结符放在一起，并检查它们中是否有任何一个可以与
input. Okay, that's the general plan. Now, let's see how this works for some specific
输入。好的，这就是总体计划。现在，让我们看看这是如何工作的，对于一些特定的
productions, and we'll just use the same grammar that we used in the last video.
制作，我们将只使用上一个视频中使用的语法。
The first production of that grammar is e goes to t and now we wanted to do is we
这个语法的第一个结果是e to t，现在我们想要做的是
want to write the functions that are needed to decide whether this production
我想要编写决定此生产是否需要的函数
matches some input. And this one happens to be simplicity itself and it's easy to
匹配一些输入。而这个恰好是简单性本身，很容易
see why. So we're, first of all, we're writing the function e1, this is the
看看为什么。所以我们，首先，我们写的是函数E1，这是
function that deals with the first production for e and succeeds returns true
处理e的第一个结果并成功的函数返回true
only if this production succeeds in matching some input. Well. How would this
只有在此产品成功匹配某些输入的情况下。井。这是怎么回事
production match any input? Well it can only match some input if some production
生产是否与任何投入相匹配？嗯，它只能与一些投入相匹配，如果一些生产
of t matches the input and we have name for that function, that's the function t
匹配输入，我们有该函数的名称，这就是函数t
which tries all the different productions for t. So e1 succeeds returns true exactly
它尝试t的所有不同结果。因此，e1 SUCCESS恰好返回TRUE
when t succeeds returns true and that's all there is to this first production. For
当t成功时，返回TRUE，这就是第一个结果的全部内容。为
the second production, we have a little more work to do. Now, e will succeed if t
第二部，我们还有一些工作要做。现在，如果你能做到这一点，我们就会成功。
+ e can match some of the input and how does that work? Well first, t has to match
+e可以匹配一些输入，这是如何工作的？首先，t必须匹配
some of the input so some production of t has to match a portion of the input and
一些输入，所以t的一些结果必须与输入的一部分相匹配，并且
after that, we have to find a + in the input following whatever t matched and if
在那之后，我们必须在输入中找到一个+，跟在匹配的t后面，如果
+ matches then, some production for e has to match some portion of the input. And
+匹配，e的一些结果必须匹配输入的某一部分。和
notice the use of the short circuiting double end here. So this is actually
请注意此处使用的短路双端。所以这实际上是
important where you're exploiting the semantics of do uble end and C and C++
重要的是您要在哪里利用double end以及C和C++的语义
which evaluates. The arguments to the double end in left to right orders. So
它会评估。双端的参数按从左到右的顺序排列。所以
first, t will execute and notice that t has embedded within its side effects on
首先，t将执行并注意到t已经嵌入到它的副作用中。
the pointer into the input. So it's incrementing the next pointer and
将指针指向输入。所以它会递增下一个指针
incrementing exactly however far t makes it. So whatever t manages to match, the
精确地递增，不管距离有多远。因此，无论t设法匹配到什么，
next pointer will advance that far. When this function returns, it's left pointing
下一个指针会前进那么远。当此函数返回时，它指向左侧
to the next terminal that t did not match and that needs to be a plus. And the call
到t不匹配的下一个终端，这需要一个加号。还有那通电话
of term will increment the next pointer again which is exactly where e should pick
将再次递增下一个指针，这正是e应该选择的位置
up and whatever e can match it will increment the next pointer just beyond
向上，无论与之匹配的是什么e，都会将下一个指针递增到略高于
that. So, that the rest of the grammar outside of this particular call can match
那。因此，此特定调用之外的语法睡觉可以匹配
it And then notice that this particular function is called e2 because this is the
然后注意，这个特定的函数被称为e2，因为这是
function for the second production for e. Well, we have one more thing to deal with
第二次生产的功能。嗯，我们还有一件事要处理。
for e and that is the function e itself. We need to write the function that will
这就是函数e本身。我们需要编写一个函数，该函数将
match any alternative for e and since it's only these two productions, it just has to
匹配e的任何替代方案，因为它只有这两个产品，所以它必须
match one of these two productions And that; this is where the backtracking is
匹配这两个产品中的一个；这就是回溯的地方
dealt with. Now the only bit of state that we have to worry about in the backtracking
处理好了。现在我们在回溯过程中唯一需要担心的是
Is this next pointer so that needs to be restored if we ever have to undo our
下一个指针是否需要恢复，如果我们必须撤消
decisions. And so the way we accomplish that is we just have a local variable to
决定。所以我们实现这一点的方法是，我们只需要一个局部变量
this function called save that records the position of the next pointer before we do
此函数调用save，在我们执行此操作之前记录下一个指针的位置
anything. So before we try to match any input, we just remember where the next
什么都行。因此，在尝试匹配任何输入之前，我们只需记住下一个
point started when this function was called. Okay? And now to do to, to do the
调用此函数时开始的点。好吧?现在去做，去做
alternative matching, we first try e1. And we see if it succeeds and if it, if it
替代匹配，我们首先尝试E1。我们看看它是否成功，如果它，如果它
doesn't succeed, actually let's do the succeeds case first. If this succeeds, if
不成功，其实让我们先做成功的案例。如果此操作成功，如果
this returns true then The semantics of double or here, it means we don't evaluate
这将返回TRUE，然后返回DOUBLE的语义，否则在这里，它意味着我们不求值
e2 so this will not be evaluated. The second component here will not be
E2，因此不会对其进行评估。这里的第二个组件不会是
evaluated if e1, if e1 returns true. It'll short circuit cuz it knows that it's going
如果E1返回TRUE，则求值为E1。它会短路，因为它知道它会
be tru e no matter what and it'll just stop there. And notice that whatever side
不管发生什么，都要真诚，事情就到此为止了。请注意，无论哪一方
effects e1 has on the next pointer will be retained and will remember and when we
E1对下一个指针的影响将被保留，并将记住
return true, the next pointer will be left pointing to the next piece of unconsumed
返回TRUE，则下一个指针将指向下一个未使用的
input. Now, let's consider what happens if e1 returns false. Well if e1 returns
输入。现在，让我们考虑一下如果E1返回False会发生什么。如果E1回来了
false, well then the only way this or can be true is if the second component is
假，那么这个或可以为真的唯一方式是如果第二个组件是
true. And what's the first thing we do? The first thing we do is restore the next
没错。我们要做的第一件事是什么？我们要做的第一件事是恢复下一个
pointer. Okay, before we try e2. And if each returns true, then the whole thing
指针。好的，在我们尝试e2之前。如果每个结果都是真的，那么整件事
returns true and, and the e function succeeds. If the e function fails, well
返回TRUE AND，e函数成功。如果e函数失败，那么
they were out of alternatives for e and the failure is gonna be returned to the
他们别无选择，失败将被送回
next higher level production, in our derivation and it will have to backtrack
下一个更高水平的生产，在我们的派生中，它将不得不回溯
and try another alternative. Now finally, what about this particular statement next
再试试另一种选择。现在最后，下面这句特别的话是怎么说的呢
= save here. Well, this is not strictly needed. Notice that here we save the next
=保存在此处。嗯，这并不是严格需要的。请注意，这里我们保存了下一个
pointer in the save variable and then the first thing, the very first thing we do if
指针放在save变量中，然后第一件事，我们要做的第一件事是
we copy it back over the next again. This is just for uniformity to make all the
我们再把它复制回下一个。这只是为了统一，以使所有的
productions look the same but since this is the very first production, we actually
产品看起来是一样的，但是因为这是第一次生产，所以我们实际上
don't need this assignment statement if we don't want to have it. So let's turn our
如果我们不想要这个赋值语句，就不需要它。所以让我们把我们的
attention to the non-terminal t. There are three productions. The first one is the t
注意非终结点t。有三部作品。第一个是t
goes to int. And that's a simple one to write. We just have to match the terminal
转到INT。这是一个写起来很简单的问题。我们只需要匹配航站楼
int so the next thing in the input has to be an integer and if it is, then t1
因此输入中的下一项必须是整数，如果是，则t1
succeeds. T2 is slightly more complex. That's the production int t, t goes to
成功了。T2稍微复杂一些。这就是生产int t，t要去的地方
int t so we have to match an int in the input followed by a followed by
所以我们必须在输入中匹配一个int，后面跟一个
something that matches any production of t. The third production is t goes to (e).
与t的任何乘积相匹配的东西。第三个乘积是t到(E)。
So, what has to happen? We have to match an open-paren first and then. Something
那么，该怎么做呢？我们必须先配上一个开阔的帕伦，然后再配上一个。某物
that matches one of the productions of e, we call the function e there and then
匹配e的一个乘积，我们在那里调用函数e，然后
finally a close-paren. And then putting all three of these together in the
最后是一个势均力敌的伙伴。然后把这三个放在一起
function t that tries all three alternatives, we just have exactly the
函数t，该函数尝试所有三种可选方案，我们只有
same structure we had for e. So we saved the current input pointer and then we try
与e的结构相同。因此我们保存了当前输入指针，然后尝试
the alternatives t1, t2 and t3 in order and each step we restore the input point
方案T1、T2和T3按顺序排列，每一步我们都恢复输入点
before we try the next alternative. Start the parser up, we have to initialize the
在我们尝试下一个替代方案之前。启动解析器，我们必须初始化
next pointer to point to the first token in the input stream and we have to invoke
Next指针指向输入流中的第一个令牌，我们必须调用
the function that matches anything derivable from the start symbols. So in
与可从起始符号派生的任何内容相匹配的函数。所以在
this case, that's just the function e. And recursive descent parsers are really easy
在本例中，这只是函数e。递归下降解析器非常简单
to implement by hand. In fact, people often do implement them by hand and just
手工实施手工实施事实上，人们经常手工实现它们，而且只是
following the discipline that I showed the previous slides. To wrap up this video,
遵循我在前面的幻灯片中展示的规则。为了结束这段视频，
let's work through a complete example. So here's our grammar, and here is all the
让我们来完成一个完整的示例。所以这是我们的语法，这是所有的
code for the recursive descent parser for this grammar and here is the input that
此语法的递归下降解析器的代码，下面是
we'll be looking at and we're gonna just mark the next pointer pointing to the
我们将查看，我们只需标记下一个指针，指向
initial token of the input, all right? And I'll also draw the Parse Tree that we're
输入的初始令牌，好吗？我还会画出我们正在
constructing at the same time. So we'll begin by invoking the start symbol so,
同时施工。因此，我们将从调用开始符号开始，
we're gonna be trying to derive something from e. And the first thing we'll do is
我们会试着从e派生出一些东西。我们要做的第一件事是
we'll try the first production. So we'll try e1, and what does e1 do? E1 is going
我们将试试看第一部作品。那么我们将尝试E1，那么E1做什么呢？E1要走了
to try t. It's gonna try to derive something from t. So, our possible Parse
来尝试t。它会尝试从t中推导出一些东西。所以，我们可能的解析
Tree looks like this. And so we invoke t and what is t going to do is we're going
树是这样的。所以我们调用t，我们要做的是
to try all three productions for t in order and so I was gonna call t1 and we'll
来按顺序尝试所有三部作品，所以我要打电话给T1，我们将
see that t1 is going to fail because it's going try it an int so I won't put it in
看到t1将失败，因为它将尝试一个int，所以我不会将其放入
the parse tree since it isn't going to work but the int is not going to match the
语法分析树，因为它不会工作，但是int不会与
open-paren. So that's going to return false which will cause us to backtrack. It
敞开-帕伦。所以这将返回假，这将导致我们回溯。它
will reset The, the input pointer, okay? And, to the beginning of the string and
会重新设置输入指针，好吗？并且，添加到字符串的开头，并且
then it'll try t2. And t2 is also going to ask, well is the input pointer = an int?
那么它将尝试T2。T2也会问，输入指针=整数吗？
And recall that the term function here always increments the input pointer. So in
回想一下，这里的术语函数总是递增输入指针。所以在
fact, this pointer is going to move over one, one tok en but this is going to
事实上，这个指针会移动到1，1个标记的上方，但这是
return false because int doesn't match open-paren. So we'll come back here. The
返回false，因为int与open-paren不匹配。所以我们会回到这里。这个
input point will be restored back to the beginning of the string and then it's
输入点将恢复到字符串的开头，然后
gonna try the alternative t3. Now, when we finally get the t3, something good is
我要试试另一种T3。现在，当我们最终拿到T3的时候，好消息是
going to happen. First thing it's going to do is going to ask is the first thing in
会发生的。它要做的第一件事就是问
input an open-paren, And in fact, it is. And so the input pointer will advance to
输入一个开放的Paren，事实上，它就是。因此输入指针将前进到
point to the int. And then it's going to try to match something derivable from e so
指向int。然后它会试着匹配从e派生出来的东西，所以
now we have our first recursive call to e. We're back here at e and it's going to try
现在我们有了对e的第一个递归调用。
e1 first and then e2. And so it calls e1 and e1 will only match something if it can
先是e1，然后是e2。所以它调用e1，并且e1只有在可能的情况下才会匹配
match t. Okay, so this is, we're down here inside of e now and now we're going to
匹配t。好的，这就是，我们现在在e里面，现在我们要
call t. And what's t going to do was going to try all three productions for t in
打电话给t。t要做的是尝试所有三部作品。
order. The first one of which happens to be the single token int and that is going
请遵守秩序。其中第一个恰好是单个令牌int，它将
to match. It's going to call term int; t1 is calling term int so that matches the
来匹配。它将调用术语int；t1调用术语int，因此它与
next token in the input stream. So, we're happy about that. The input pointer
输入流中的下一个令牌。所以，我们对此感到高兴。输入指针
advances again. And now, we return through all these levels of calls. T1 succeeds
再次前进。现在，我们回到所有这些级别的电话中。T1成功
which means that t succeeds, which means that e succeeds. Okay. And now we're back
这意味着t成功了，这意味着e成功了。好吧。现在我们又回来了
here in the production for t3 and we're going to ask well is the next thing that
在T3的制作过程中，我们要问的是下一件事
we see in the input a close-paren? And it did it is and so a close-paren we'll be
我们在输入中看到了一个势均力敌的伙伴？它做到了，所以我们将是势均力敌的伙伴
recorded. And now t3 will succeed which means that t succeeds, this t succeeds and
已录制。现在t3成功了，这意味着t成功了，这个t成功了，
finally we'll return to the root call e and that returns true which means that the
最后，我们将返回根调用e，它返回true，这意味着
Parse succeeded. That plus the fact that we are now at the end of the input, there
解析成功。再加上我们现在处于输入的末尾，
is no more input to consume and we have returned from the start symbol with true
不再有要使用的输入，并且我们从开始符号返回的值为true
and so we have successfully parse the input string.
因此，我们已经成功地解析了输入字符串。